But back to the Google experience,
Mas voltando à experiência do Google,
you have probably used one or more of our 4,000 models.
você provavelmente usou um ou mais dos nossos 4.000 modelos.
I talked about how deep learning has come a long way in
Falei sobre como o aprendizado profundo percorreu um longo caminho
the past few years and nothing illustrates that better than Google Photos.
nos últimos anos, e nada ilustra isso melhor do que o Google Fotos.
This is the Google product where you can upload photos from
Esse é o produto do Google em que você pode enviar fotos
your camera to the cloud and you don't need to tag it.
da sua câmera para a nuvem sem precisar marcá-las.
The ML software tags images for you so that you can then find images. Let me show you.
O software de ML marca as imagens para que você possa encontrá-las.
So I'm going to go to photos.google.com and type in Ladakh.
Vou acessar photos.google.com e digitar Ladakh.
Ladakh is this beautiful place in the Tibetan plateau that I went to a few years ago.
Ladakh é uma região linda do planalto tibetano para onde fui há alguns anos.
Let me go ahead and type in Ladakh and you notice
Vou digitar Ladakh, e você verá
that Google Photos brings me back images from 2011,
que o Google Fotos me traz imagens de 2011
and it basically finds the beautiful Ladakh Valley.
e encontra o belo Vale de Ladakh.
It goes ahead and finds a Buddhist monastery in Ladakh.
Ele encontra um mosteiro budista em Ladakh.
Interestingly enough, it even finds Himalayan peaks that I photographed on the way there.
Ele encontra até os picos do Himalaia que fotografei no caminho até lá.
And I had not gone ahead and tagged any of these images as being Ladakh,
E eu não tinha marcado nenhuma dessas imagens como sendo de Ladakh,
it just happened to be in the cloud.
só aconteceu de estarem na nuvem.
It's part of my photos album and I'm able
Elas fazem parte do meu álbum de fotos,
to go ahead and retrieve these photographs simply by saying,
e consigo recuperar essas fotos simplesmente dizendo:
show me all the photographs I took in Ladakh. Pretty amazing.
mostre-me todas as fotos que tirei em Ladakh. Incrível.